

IMUENTINYAN NOSARUMEN FRONTEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFO

1

+2349032379922

≥ n

nosarumenimuentinyan@gmail.co

11

www.linkedin.com/nosarum en-imuentinyan



Edo State, Nigeria.

EDUCATION

2019-2020

Frontend Web Developer Course freecodecamp.org

2015-2021

Bachelor Degree in Petroleum Engineering

University of Benin

PORTFOLIO

Visti Portfolio Website

HOBBIES

- Working out
- Learning new skills

ABOUT ME

Proficient Front End Developer effective at developing strong fast loading and responsive websites that achieve customer and business objectives. Familiar with working alongside a team to determine needs, create plans and optimize design, usability and performance. Well-versed in using Javascript and React as well as other resources to accomplish design requirements.

Prepared to offer my development experience built upon my 2 years of hard work to a growing company while I am also eager to learn and improve on my skills along the way.

EXPERIENCE

January 2022 - Present

GitHub.com

FRONTEND OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

 I contributed to an open source e-commerce project by using React to implement a functioning suggestions search bar to search available items from the API. It enabled users to scale through the items they needed better.

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Upwork.com

FREELANCE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

 I improved the performance and design of a clients portfolio website which was bootstrapped with Next.js.

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

BigTunez Entertainment Records

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

 Developed a site for my colleague who is starting a blog/entertainment news and updates company.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS



FRAMEWORKS /LIBRARIES:

Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, sass, Material UI

VERSION CONTROL: Git and Github

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1.) freeCodeCamp.org Responsive Web Design Developer Certification.
- 2.) freeCodeCamp.org JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Developer Certification.

OTHER SKILLS

- extensive knowledge of wordpress CMS.
- proficiency in use of API to request and work with data.
- studying an already existing codebase.
- proficiency in use of API to request and work with data.
- Reading and understanding API documentations.
- Effective communication skills.